(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-08-26T17:10:17.124151",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
A long, long ago in a land far, far away
lived Polka, a beautiful maiden who drew the ire of her queen for she too wished to be the prettiest being in the world.
One day, Polka was walking through the forest when she met an old woman.
"Would you like an apple? My, but these are ripe and tasty," she said.
Tempted by the offer, Polka gladly took a bite.
As Polka was spellbound by how delicious the apple was, the old woman vanished.
It was then that Polka made the realization: the Apple was poisoned.
But it was too late. Polka collapsed to the ground helplessly.
Many moons later, the fateful moment had arrived.
A prince had appeared before Polka.
He was captivated by her beauty and eventually gave her the kiss of fate...
And Polka awakened, ever so beautiful!
Her beauty had not diminished over time, as though reality was but a virtual concept to her...
Hm? But wait, Polka is a virtual idol, so poisoned apples won't work on her.
But don't get me wrong, Polka-senpai is incredibly pretty!
Now, Polka-senpai, go on and show off your reborn self as an idol!
鏡よ鏡よ鏡さん
Mirror, mirror, on the wall,
世界で一番可愛がるのはやめてよ
stop treating me like the cutest in the world.
棘のような視線迫る
Thorny gazes bear down on me,
優しいふりした彼女が
she who put on a kind facade
素敵な晩餐もてなした
prepared a wonderful dinner.
そっと口に含むと
As I gently took a bite,
薄れていく意識の中で
amidst my fading consciousness,
夢を見てる
I'm dreaming.
いつかのおとぎ話
A fairy tale of long ago,
時が止まる
where time stands still.
お願いKISSで
I pray with a kiss...
鏡よ鏡よ鏡さん
Mirror, mirror, mirror-san
世界で一番可愛がるのはやめてよ
Stop loving me the most in the world
棘のような視線迫る
Thorn-like gazes approach
優しいふりをした彼女が
She who put on a gentle act
素敵な晩餐もてなした
Served a wonderful dinner
そっと口に含んだら 微笑
Smiling as I softly tasted it
薄れてゆく意思の中で 夢を見ている
Dreaming within my fading consciousness
いつかの童話 時が止まる
An old fairy tale, time stops
お願いKISSで目を覚ませて欲しいの
Please wake me up with a kiss
白い棺から 連れ出すように
As if leading me out of a white coffin
突き刺さる憎しみは ドラマチックな事情
Piercing hatred is a dramatic affair
祈っても 王子様は まだ来ない
Even if I pray, the prince is still not here
鏡よ鏡よ鏡さん
Mirror, mirror, mirror-san
ネクタイ任せや 頬に挨拶するから
Entrusting my tie, greeting my cheeks
嫉みを買われてしまった
My envy was incurred
7人の小人はいるけど
There are seven dwarves, but
助ける素振り、知らんふりね
Acting like they'll help, feigning ignorance
そっと首を掴まれ 微笑
Gently grabbing my throat, smiling
一粒の涙さえも拭えなくて
Unable to wipe even a single teardrop
呼吸もままならない 視失った
Breathing is impossible, I lost sight
消えそうだから 早く駆けつけて欲しいの
I'm about to fade, please hurry and rush over
訳は聞けないで 応えられない
I can't ask why, I can't answer
望まない憎まれは 深い愛の二乗
Undesired hatred is the square of deep love
もうすぐで いなく成るのかな
Will I be gone very soon?
途切れてく命の音
The fading sound of life
毒リンゴを食した少女のように眠りにつく
Sleeping like a girl who ate a poison apple
お願いKISSで目を覚ませて欲しいの
Please wake me up with a kiss
胸の中の声 届きますか
Can the voice in my heart reach you?
階段を上ったらドアを開けるだけで
Just climbing the stairs and opening the door
見つかるよ ああ
You'll find me, ah
お願いKISSで目を覚ませて欲しいの
Please wake me up with a kiss
白い棺から 連れ出すように
As if leading me out of a white coffin
突き刺さる憎しみは ドラマチックな事情
Piercing hatred is a dramatic affair
祈っても 王子様は まだ来ない
Even if I pray, the prince is still not here
消えてしまう その前に
Before I disappear, before that
その前に
Before that
階段を上ったら ドアを開けるだけで
Just climbing the stairs and opening the door
見つかるよ ああ
You'll find me, ah
お願いKISSで目を覚ませて欲しいの
Please wake me up with a kiss
白い棺から 連れ出すように
As if leading me out of a white coffin
突き刺さる憎しみは ドラマチックな事情
Piercing hatred is a dramatic affair
祈っても 王子様は まだ来ない
Even if I pray, the prince is still not here
消えてしまう その前に
Before I disappear, before that
その前に
Before that
改めまして！
Let's start over!
おまるポルカです...あ、違った！えっと
It's Omaru Polka... Ah, no! Um...
違う、えっと
No, um...
このライブをご機嫌おまるポルカです！
This live is Gojigen Omaru Polka!
よろしくお願いします！
Please look forward to it!
なんでこんな改まってるかって言うと
Why am I being so formal, you ask?
やっぱり、ほら、アイドル衣装な
Well, you see, it's an idol outfit,
わけじゃないですか！
isn't it?!
あのー、いつもは、えっとサーカスの王を目指す
Um, normally, um, I act as a circus member
サーカス団員としてやってるんだけどさ
aiming to be the circus king, but...
こうやってね、改めてこのライブ皆様が通ってきた道...いやそのそれを深層にそれをどうすと、なると...
like this, re-evaluating this live, the path everyone took... wait, deep into that, what happens when we...
あ、全然違うわ！気分が
Ah, totally different! My mood...
なんか、えっすごいうわ！今気分がめちゃくちゃお姉さんな感じになっちゃったんだけど！
Man, wow, amazing! My mood just became super onee-san-like!
ああ、え、可愛いかな？
Ah, eh, is it cute?
あのね、さっきもね、みんなも見たと思うんだけど、あの、えっとねねとはお揃いの
Um, you know, as you probably saw a little while ago, Nene and I have matching...
形で、これね、あのね、いっぱい種類がある、ある、いっぱい参考っていうか、あるんだけど
shapes, and for this, you know, there are lots of types, lots of references, or rather, there are...
え、ねねとはお揃いの形になりました！後の後続組がどうなるか知らない！
Um, it became a matching shape with Nene! I don't know what the subsequent group will do!
はあ、そんな訳で、よお、ちょっと緊張してしまいました、ポルカ
Haah, anyway, wow, I got a little nervous, Polka...
なんか 本当に、
Like, really...
来るんだ 来るんだと思ってましたけど この日が遂に来るんだと、
I knew it would come, I really did, but this day has finally arrived,
あとこれ2回ぐらい繰り返されますからね、
and this gets repeated like two more times, so—
ま、遂にこの日がやってきたんだと。
well, this day has finally come.
はい。ありがとう。
Yeah. Thank you.
今日はちょっとじゃあちょっと、えー、コールレスしていいかな？
Today, let's see, um... can I do a call-and-response?
え、あ、だめだ、アイドルこんなポーズじゃいかん。
Wait, no, an idol shouldn't be making a pose like that.
コールレスしていいかなー！
Can I do a call-and-response?!
えー、えー、おまるポルカはかわいいですかー！
Ehh, ehh, is Omaru Polka cute?!
うーん、もっと！もっと！せーの！
Yeah— More! More! Ready, set!
おー！いいぞ！もっと！いいぞ！いいぞ！
Oh! That's it! More! That's it! That's it!
かわいい！かわいい！かわいい！あー、ありがとう！
Cute! Cute! Cute! Ah, thank you!
今の、大丈夫だったかな？ちゃんと、
Was that okay just now? Did I do it right?
あのね、ひみね、あの、チアポルカの人が多いからさ、ポルカのことかわいいよって言えない人も、
You know, since there are a lot of cheer-Polka fans, even those who usually can't bring themselves to call Polka cute—
今だったら言えるかも。今、今しかない、逆に今しかないよ！
You can probably say it now! Now's your chance, or rather, now's your only chance!
どう？かわいいかな？
How is it? Am I cute?
よし、もう一回ちょっと、もうそれじゃあちょっと、照れ、
Alright, let's do it one more time. Well, if I keep going, I'll get all shy—
ちょっとあの、ガチの照れが入っちゃうんで、あの、いや、やめやめ、
Wait, um, genuine shyness is starting to creep in, so, um, no, never mind—
で、どんどん下がっちゃった！
And I just ended up sinking down lower!
はい。ね。
Right. You know.
これね、あの、えっと、ポルカの見てほしい点としては、大きいリボンですかね。
And, um, another highlight of Polka I'd like you to see is this big ribbon, right?
あと、お星様がね、髪の毛につきましたよと。どういうこっちゃねこれ。かわいいでしょ！
And look, a little star got attached to my hair, too. What's that about? Isn't it cute?!
いや、このね、形すごいあこがれてたんだ。なんかポルカっていつのさ、あの、
Man, I've always really admired this shape. You know, since Polka's...
サーカス衣装がそもそもタンクトップだから、ちょっと、あのね、逆にース！みたい。どっちの方が、あ、安心した。
Circus outfit is a tank top to begin with, so, um, conversely it's super pure? Which is better? Ah, I feel relieved.
いいや、これで落ち着いた。なんかすごいね、これ、腕にこんなのもついてるんだよ！
Anyway, this calms me down. Wow, look at this, I even have these attached to my arms!
はー、先輩とおそろいになったし！同期でこれです、これからライブもできるし、
Ah, I'm matching with my seniors now! And with my generation mates, we can do live shows like this, too,
あー！はい、というわけでね、ライブぜひね、えっと、楽しみにしてください。あの、3月の、みんらのライブもね、楽しみにしていてください。
Ah! Right, so please look forward to our live shows, um... Please look forward to everyone's live performance in March, too.
というわけで何これなんか、あれしよう、あれ。すっくしょうタイム？違うか。撮影会タイム？
So what's this, let's do... that. Screenshot time? No wait. Photo-shoot time?
なんか、ポルカ1年半くらいにして初めてなんか違う意味の羞恥心を今知ってるんだけど。
It's like, for the first time in about a year and a half, Polka is experiencing a whole new level of embarrassment.
待って、えっとね、えっと、えー、こ、こういう、えなんだろう、ピース？普通にピースかな？
Wait, um, let's see... what kind of pose? Like this? A peace sign? Just a normal peace sign?
あ、わかんない、なんかもうててててててて。えっと、こんな感じ？
Ah, I don't know, my hands are just shaking. Um, something like this?
え、あ、じゃあ近づいてさ、今日は楽しんでるか？みんな愛してるぞ！好きだぞ！
Hey, ah, let's get closer. Are you having fun today? I love you all! I adore you!
こんなライブで言ったことないわ。恥ずかしい、はずかし、はずかし、なんか、
I've never said things like that at a live before. It's so embarrassing, embarrassing...
ごめん、今日1人で笑ってばっかだわ。全然もうアイドルって何かかんないけど、
Sorry, I've just been laughing by myself today. I have no idea what being an idol is, but—
えと、これからも立派にこのライブ動かして、おまるポルカとして頑張っていきます！
Um, I will keep delivering wonderful lives and do my best as Omaru Polka!
やばい、このポーズじゃない絶対違う。えっと、ピース？えっと、えっと、ニコ？
Oh no, this pose is definitely wrong. Um, peace sign? Let's see, a smile?
わかんないな、もうててててててて。飛び切りかわいい！おまるポルカ！よし！
I have no idea, my hands are all fluttering. Super cute! Omaru Polka! Alright!
ええと、はい、あのですね、えっと、ちょっとこんなにずっと落ち着きがないの、本当に初披露の時以来なんですけど、
Um, yes, so, um... I haven't been this restless and nervous since my very first debut reveal,
この後、なんと！今日はリレーなんだな！
but after this, guess what! Today is a relay stream!
ラミィちゃんの配信、そしてそのあとが最後獅子白で、朝じゃないや、獅子白で、みんなと、
Lamy-chan's stream, and then after that, finally Shishiro— no, not morning, Shishiro's stream, and with everyone—
みんなのライブするんでよかったら来てくださーい！ハッシュタグは、
we're doing a live show, so please come check it out! The hashtag is,
えっと、えっと、シャープ、ねぽらぼ、あ、ねぽらぼアイドル衣装でよろしくお願いします！
um... #NepolaboIdolCostume, please check it out!
まだまだ、えっと、今日は始まったばかり、解散ねえで、というわけで、
Today has only just begun, we're not disbanding yet, so—
これは、これは、え、ちょ、え、わかんない、何をすればいいのかわかんないこうやって。
What is this... um, I don't even know what I should be doing right now.
えっとな、えっと、じゃあ最後の挨拶いきます！
Um, well then, let's do our final closing greeting!
せーの、バイバーイ！バイバーイ！これからもよろしく、本当に本当に、この服着させてくれてありがとう！おまるポルカでしたー！
Ready, set, bye-bye! Bye-bye! Thank you so much for letting me wear this outfit! This was Omaru Polka!
尾丸ポルカ アイドル衣装
Omaru Polka Idol Costume